"六人行"前情介绍…
Previously on Friends:
我已经等了17个小时
Seventeen hours, I have been at this.
- 我张开了几公分   - 三公分
- How many centimeters am I dilated?     - Three.
只有三公分 我才是张开了三公分
Just three? I'm dilated three.
- 我们总是说以后要生孩子   - 我们要试试看吗
- We've talk about having babies someday.     - So we're gonna try?
- 在这里    - 不是这里
- Right here?     - No, not here.
或许吧
Maybe here.
这是你外婆的订婚戒指
This is your grandmother's engagement ring.
我要你把它送给瑞秋
I want you to give it to Rachel.
- 妈 不   - 罗斯 她不是你在酒吧…
- Mom, no.     - Ross, this isn't just some girl...
泡到就上的女孩
...you picked up in a bar and humped.
- 我想你是来探病的   - 对
- Hey, I take it you're visiting someone?     - Uh-huh, yeah.
- 如果你有时问想拜访其他人…   - 对 我很乐意
- Wanna visit someone else?     - Yeah, I would like that.
- 就是他   - 太棒了 去找他吧
- That's him.     - Great. Well, go get him.
或许你该先进去
Or maybe you could go in first.
嗨 我是德瑞克·拉莫瑞医生 我得问你几个例行的问题
Hi, I'm Dr. Drake Ramoray. I have a few routine questions.
你会跟女人上了床后 不再打电话给她们吗
Do you sleep with women and never call them again?
天啊
Oh, my God.
（急诊救护车）
我们该告诉瑞秋 她隔壁就有一间单人待产室吗
Should we tell Rachel there's an empty, private room right next door to hers?
没错 或许我们可以在这里做爱
We could. Or we could have sex in it.
让我边脱裤子边想
Well, let me think about that. While I remove my pants.
好吧 先生 来造人吧
Okay, mister. Fertilize me.
那是珍妮丝的声音吗
Does that sound like Janice?
如果不是的话 就是有个人很像她
If it's not, then there's two of them.
那表示世界末日到了
And that would mean it's the end of the world.
# 没有人告诉你活着有多累 #
# So no one told you life was gonna be this way #
# 上班受罪 口袋空空 爱情变累赘 #
# Your job's a joke, you're broke, your love life's D.O.A. #
# 寂寞又潦倒 受气又受累 #
# It's like you're always stuck in second gear #
# 日复一日 年复一年 #
# When it hasn't been your day, #
# 时运不济 活着受罪 #
# your week, your month, or even your year #
# 你我永不离弃 #
# but I'll be there for you #
# 你我相偎相依 #
# 'Cause you're there for me too #
嘿
Hey.
- 嘿   - 嗨
- Hey.     - Hi.
我不敢相信要这么久 你还好吗
I can't believe this is taking so long. How are you doing?
还不错 你知道试着
Oh, not bad. You know that feeling...
将圣柏纳犬从屁股谁出来的感觉吗
...when you're trying to blow a Saint Bernard out your ass?
真的太奇怪了 我听到…
Weirdest thing. Did I hear...?
天啊 是真的
Mother of God, it's true.
钱德宾
Chandler Bing.
珍妮丝
Janice.
不只那样 珍妮丝要生了 她正在阵痛
Notjust Janice. Janice in labor. Contracting and everything.
这应该很容易 我的骨盆很宽
Oh, this should be easy. I have a very wide pelvis.
你应该记得 钱德
You remember, Chandler.
珍妮丝 我不知道你怀孕了
Janice, I didn't know you were pregnant.
你偷走了哪个笨蛋的心
Who's the unwitting human whose essence you've stolen?
这是你的孩子
It's you.
This is yours.
什么
What?
看他有多紧张 我们好几年没上过床了
Ha, look how nervous he gets! We haven't slept together in years!
那真的很有趣 会痛吗 生产会痛吗
That's funny. Does it hurt? Does the labor hurt?
好吧 我想到一个 如果非吃不可 你要吃哪一个
Okay, I've got one for you. If you had to, which would you rather eat?
千里眼的小狗或会说话的猩猩
A Seeing Eye dog or a talking gorilla?
我猜是会说话的猩猩
I'd have to say the talking gorilla.
因为至少我可以跟他解释 是你逼我吃掉他
Because at least I could explain to him that you're making me eat him.
- 有人读过大学   - 对
- Oh. Somebody went to college.     - Yeah.
怎么了 对不起
Wow. What is it? I'm sorry.
对不起 我的脚好痒
Oh, I'm sorry. It's just my foot itches like crazy.
让我来吧
Oh. I'll get it.
通常我会跟女人混熟后才会让她用汤匙帮我搔痒
Wow. I usually get to know a girl better before I let her spoon me.
别激动 它不是叉子
Relax. It's not like we're forking.
一共是五个 罗斯 五个女人生了五个孩子…
Oh, that's five, Ross. Five women have had five babies...
我还是没生
...and I have had no babies.
她为什么不肯出来
Why doesn't she want to come out?
你知道我在想什么吗
You know what I think it is?
我想九个月来…
I think you made such a nice home for her...
她在你的身体里很舒服 所以她不想离开
...over the last nine months that she just doesn't want to leave.
你甚至在瞎掰哄我
Oh. Look at you making up crap for me.
- 天啊   - 好吧
- Oh, God. Ooh, ooh...     - Okay. Okay.
21小时 你是英雄
Twenty-one hours. You're a hero.
医生 你得想想办法 给我药…
Doctor, you gotta do something. You gotta give me drugs...
或是放火把她熏出来
...or you gotta light a fire up in there and just smoke it out.
事实上 我想你可以进产房了
Actually, I think you're ready to go to the delivery room.
- 什么   - 开了10公分了
- What?     - Ten centimeters.
你快当妈妈了
You're about to become a mom.
天啊 好吧
Oh, my God. Okay.
打败你了 混蛋 宝贝
Ha-ha-ha, beat you, sucker. Oh, baby.
天啊 他就是刚刚来看过我的医生
Oh, my God. That's the doctor who was in my room before.
好吧 幻想先生
Oh. Okay, Mr. Percocet.
我是说 电视里的那个人刚刚来过…
I'm telling you, the guy from that show was here...
还问了我一些怪问题
...in my room, asking me all these weird questions.
克利夫 你真的相信电视明星来过你的房间
Cliff, do you really believe that a character from a TV show was here in your room?
瑞秋要生了
Rachel's having her baby.
就是他 你认识他
That's him. You know him?
好吧 我…好吧
Okay. Okay. I... Okay. Um... This...
我派我朋友乔伊来调查你
I sent my friend, Joey, in here to find out stuff about you.
如果…如果你想知道的话 我们觉得你是个好人
Um, if it, you know... If it helps, you came off great.
比现在的我好多了
A lot better than I'm coming off right now.
我不敢相信 你要他假扮医生
I don't believe this. You got him to pretend he was some fake doctor?
假扮 对不起 哈罗
Fake? Excuse me? Hello?
你要我以为自己疯了
And then you tried to make me think that I was crazy?
那是不对的 我非常抱歉
You're right, that was wrong. I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
那只是因为我非常喜欢你 我们能重新开始吗
It's just that I liked you so much. Can we just start over?
我不那么认为
I don't think so.
我可以说话吗
Uh, if I may?
你跟我透露了很多你的私事
Look, Cliff, you told me a lot of personal stuff about you, right?
或许你应该知道一些关于她的私事
Now, maybe it would help if you knew some personal stuff about her.
她曾跟男同志冰舞选手结婚
Uh, she was married to a gay ice dancer.
她帮她弟弟生下三胞胎
Uh, she gave birth to her brother's triplets.
她的双胞胎姊姊是A片女优
Oh, oh, oh. Her twin sister used to do porn.
- 我们不想听那些疯狂的事   - 对
- Joey, we're trying to dial down the crazy.     - Right.
我们并不认识彼此 要忘了这些很容易…
Look, we don't really know each other, so it'd be really easy to just forget this...
但我们对彼此有感觉 我不知道你是怎么样…
...but there seems to be something between us. And I don't know about you...
但我不是常常遇到这种事
...but that doesn't happen to me a lot.
- 我也是   - 我也是
- It doesn't happen to me, either.     - Me, neither.
用力
Push.Push.
你得再用力推五秒
We're gonna push for five more seconds.
五 四…
Five, four...
三  二 一
Three, two, one. Oh!
下一次阵痛是20秒后
Okay, the next contraction should be in about 20 seconds.
- 我没办法再用力了   - 你表现的很好
- I can't. I can't push anymore.     - Sweetie, you're doing great.
天啊 还要20秒耶
Oh, God. Twenty seconds, my ass!
来吧 继续用力
Here we go. Okay, keep pushing.
- 来吧   - 推 等一下
- Come on.     - Push. Wait.
- 我看到东西了   - 什么 真的吗 我的天啊
- I see something.     - What, you do? You do? Oh, my God.
别说"我的天啊" 什么
Don't say "Oh, my God." "Oh, my God," what?
那是什么
What is that?
宝宝的屁股 她倒过来了
That's the baby's buttocks. She's breech.
- 我以为她有两个头   - 天啊
- Oh, my God. I thought she had two heads.     - Oh, God.
她没事吧
Is she gonna be okay?
- 她没事的   - 好吧
- She's gonna be fine.     - Yeah.
她的胎位不正 你得更用力推
She's in a more difficult position, so you're gonna have to push harder.
- 好吧   - 就是那样 推
- Okay.     - Go. Come on. Go. Go.
你得更用力推
Rachel, you're gonna have to push harder.
- 抱歉 我办不到   - 不 我知道你办得到
- I'm sorry, I can't. I can't.     - Yes, you can. I know you can do this.
我不知道 拜托 帮我推吧
I had no idea. please, you do it for me.
来吧 再一次 最后一次 准备好了吗 一 二 三
Let's go. One more time. One final push. Ready? One, two, three.
很好
Good.
继续用力
Keep pushing.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
你不知道那有多痛
You have no idea how much this hurts.
继续用力
Keep going! Keep going!
好了
Here we go.
宝宝胎位不正 但她要出来了
Oh, oh! She's upside down, but she's coming. She's coming.
- 天啊   - 我的天啊
- Oh, God!     - Oh. Oh, my God.
天啊 她出来了
Oh, my God, she's here.
她太完美了
Oh, she's perfect.
哇 她好小
Oh, wow. Oh, she's so tiny.
- 她要去哪里    - 他们得先把她包起来
- Where'd she go?     - They're just wrapping her up.
好吧 小心一点 她真的很小
Okay. Well, be careful with her, she's really tiny.
她来了
Here she is.
小家伙
Oh, you.
谢谢你终于出来了
Oh, thanks for coming out of me.
我知道
I know. Oh.
对
Yes. Oh.
她在看我 嗨 我认识你
Oh, she's looking at me. Hi. I know you.
- 你们取好名字了吗    - 还没有
- Do we have a name yet?     - No, not yet.
没关系 先叫她葛林之女
That's fine. For now we'll just call her Baby Girl Green.
不 盖勒·葛林之女
Oh, no. Baby Girl Geller-Green.
嗨 小女孩
Hello, Baby Girl.
- 我们能进去吗    - 请进
- Can we come in?     - Oh, come on in.
- 她在那里   - 她好漂亮
- Oh, there she is.     - Oh, she's so beautiful.
来吧
Here.
天啊 她好神奇
Oh, my God. She's amazing.
我很高兴你们喝醉后上了床
Oh, I'm so glad you guys got drunk and had sex.
太不可思议了 前一分钟她还在你肚子里…
It's incredible. I mean, one minute she's inside you...
47小时后她就出现了
...and then 47 hours later, here she is.
她看起来好真实
She looks so real.
你们了解我的意思
You know what I mean.
- 好了 轮到我了   - 菲比阿姨
- Okay, my turn. My turn.     - Aunt Phoebe.
宝贝 你好可爱
Yes. Oh, baby. Oh, you're so cute.
我可以捏碎你小小的头
Oh, I could squeeze your little head.
我不会那么做的
I won't.
- 甜心 怎么了    - 没事 我只是不由自主地哭了
- Honey, what's the matter?     - Nothing. Sorry, I just can't stop crying.
医生说这很正常 都是荷尔蒙害的
The doctor said it's completely normal, with the hormones...
- 而且我还会睡不着   - 你们都会失眠
-...plus you're sleep-deprived.     - So? You guys are all sleep-deprived.
我没看过你因为鞋子穿错脚就哭个不停
I don't see you weeping because you put your slippers on the wrong feet.
天啊
Oh, God.
- 怎么了    - 我又想起来了
- What's the matter now?     - I was reliving it.
你们帮她取好名字了吗
So do you know what you're gonna call her yet?
等一下 她不是叫女儿吗
Oh. Wait a minute, it's not gonna be Baby Girl?
我觉得那个名字很有创意
I thought that was so original.
事实上 我们正在考虑两个名字
Uh, actually, we've narrowed it down to two names.
你知道吗 两个名字我都很喜欢
Yeah, and you know what? I love them both.
你们帮忙挑一个
So why don't you just pick one, and that'll be it.
好吧 大伙们…
Wow, um, okay. Uh, everyone?
她是伊莎贝儿
This is Isabella.
-嗨 伊莎贝儿   - 嗨
- Hi, Isabella.     - Hi.
- 什么   - 那不是她的名字
- What?     - That's not her name.
抱歉 她感觉上不像伊莎贝儿
I'm sorry, she just doesn't feel like an Isabella.
- 另一个名字是什么    - 笛莉拉
- What was the other one, Ross?     - Um, Delilah.
太棒了 突然间她成了圣经里的妓女
Oh, great. Suddenly she sounds like a biblical whore.
我猜还是叫她女儿吧
Ahem, so I guess we're back to Baby Girl.
我们该怎么办
What are we gonna do?
- 没关系 你们会想到好名字的   - 你说的倒容易
- It's okay, honey. You'll find a name.     - Ugh. Easy for you to say.
你已经知道你的孩子要叫什么名字了
You already know what your kids' names are gonna be.
- 是吗    - 我14岁时就帮他们取好了名字
- You do?     - Yeah. I had them picked out since I was 14.
不 你的宝宝会以点心或烘烤食物的名字来命名吧
Oh, no, it's gonna be named after some snack or baked good, isn't it?
告诉我们你想了什么名字
Well, tell us, what are they?
好吧 如果是男孩的话就叫丹尼尔
Um, okay. If it's a boy, it's Daniel.
- 如果是女孩呢    - 我不想说
- And if it's a girl?     - I don't want to say.
少来了 告诉我们 我们不会抢走它的
Oh, stop. Tell us. We're not gonna want it.
好吧 她叫艾玛
Okay. It's Emma.
艾玛
Emma.
看吧 我不喜欢它
See, I don't want it.
- 拿去吧   - 什么
- Take it.     - What?
她真的很适合叫艾玛
She's clearly an Emma.
甜心 但你喜欢那个名字
Oh, honey, but you love that name.
对 但我更爱你
Yeah. But I love you more.
而且什么名字都跟宾不配 所以我是死定了
Besides, you know, nothing goes with Bing. So I'm screwed.
亚朗·利普曼·古拉尼要跟他未来的新娘打个招呼
Aaron Lipman-Guralnick would like to say hello to his future bride.
他真的会让人说不出话来 对吧
Wow, he kind of takes your breath away, doesn't he?
他是个谦虚的人
He's a keeper. Ha, ha.
- 你觉得如何    - 我很好
- How are you feeling?     - Oh, you know, I'm fine.
我真的很佩服你做的事
Can I just say, I really admire what you're doing.
你要自己抚养她
Just raising her all alone.
我不是一个人 我有罗斯
Oh, I'm not doing it alone. I have Ross.
现在是的
Oh, sure. Now.
如果他认识别人结了婚 那时又会是怎么样的呢
But what happens when he meets somebody else and gets married?
他会离婚的 那就是罗斯
Well, then he gets a divorce. It's Ross.
我得告诉你 瑞秋 听珍妮丝的话
I'm telling you, Rachel. Listen to Janice.
男人都说他们会在 但他们会成立自己的家庭
They all say they're gonna be there, until they start their real family.
罗斯不会那么做的
That's never gonna happen with Ross.
以前我也那么相信
That's what I thought about my first husband.
如果我的孩子能跟她爸及新的波霸小姐共度一个周末…
Now, I'm lucky if my kid gets to spend the weekend with her father...
那算我运气好
...and little Miss New-Boobs.
真的吗
Really?
我讨厌跟你这么说…
I hate to be the one to say it...
但你们两个得靠自己
...but, honey, you two are on your own.
那是…你知道的 那是…
Well, that's, you know, that's...
我们已经单独相处了20分钟 我们表现的很好
We've been alone for the last 20 minutes and we're doing okay.
或许我们不会孤单的
You know what? Maybe we won't be alone.
因为最近
Because lately things have been happening...
我跟罗斯之间有些事发生
...between me and Ross, you know?
我来医院前 我们还接了吻 你知道吗
And right before I went into labor, we had this kiss. You know?
或许那会是个开始
So it might be the beginning of something.
- 嗨 珍妮丝   - 嗨
- Hey, Janice.     - Oh, hi.
这个小家伙是谁
Oh. Who's this little guy?
- 亚朗 那是你未来的岳父   - 不
- Say hello to Aaron, your future son-in-law.     - Oh, no, no. Ha, ha.
- 我让你们一家人好好独处   - 好吧
- I'm gonna leave you three alone.     - Okay.
天啊 你看到那孩子的鼻子了吗
Man, you see the kid on that nose?
你知道我刚刚想到什么吗
You know what I was thinking about?
我们出门前的那个吻
Um, that kiss before we left the apartment.
那真的很特别吧
That was something, huh?
对 真的是
Yeah. Yeah, it really was.
但我们…我们得小心点
But we, we gotta be careful. Heh.
我们…你知道的 我们不能让历史重演
We...You know, we can't let that happen again, you know?
对
Right.
我们不希望再发生那种事
We don't want to go down that road, do we?
对 所以我才会跟你提这件事
No. No, of course not. No, that's why I brought it up.
- 他们没有汽水吗    - 天啊 对不起
- They didn't have any sodas?     - Oh, my God. I'm sorry.
我忙着跟护士说话 完全忘了
I was talking to this nurse. Completely forgot.
现在就已经开始了
And so it begins.
她在里面吗
She in there?
对 护士正把她放在床上 那就是她
Yeah. She's putting her down now. That's her.
- 你看 快看艾玛   - 我无法决定
- Look at Emma.     - I can't decide who she looks more like.
她长得像你或瑞秋
You or Rachel?
什么 你在开玩笑吗 她美极了 完全是瑞秋的遗传
Oh, what, are you kidding? She's gorgeous. It's all Rachel.
对不起 这是我最后一次问你 你们两个为什么不结婚
I'm sorry. For the last time, why aren't you two together again?
不 我知道 因为你们没有到那个程度
No, I know. Because you're not in that place.
那真的很棒 但事实上你们真的到了
Which would be fine, except you totally are.
情况很复杂 好吗
It's complicated, okay?
对 那是真的 你一直都爱着她
Yeah, that's true. Yeah, you love her, you always have...
你们生了一个孩子 没有答案是百分之百的正确
...you have a child together. There's no right answer.
我们曾经交往过
Look, we've been together. Okay, and then apart.
后来分手 后合后又分手
And then together, and then apart.
现在我们生了一个孩子
And now we have a baby.
如果我们又复合 结果还是不行…
It's just, if we got together again and it didn't work out?
我不会对艾玛那么做
I could never do that to Emma.
她来到这个世界 想像每件事都…这是我的想法
I mean, she came into this world thinking everything... Now me.
什么 他们在水里放东西
What, do they put something in the water in this place?
瑞秋跟我现在过得很好
It's just, Rachel and I, we're doing really well now.
我知道
I know, I know, I know.
如果你想更进一步 就得突破现状
If you try to make it more, you might wreck it.
- 没错   - 对
- Yeah, exactly.     - Right.
或许你可以得到你从15岁开始梦想的世界
Or you might get everything you've wanted since you were 15.
嘿
Hey.
我看到一个女人同时在喂双胞胎母乳
I just saw a woman breastfeeding both of her twins at the same time.
那真的很像怪物秀
It is like a freak show up here.
- 怎么了    - 没事
- What's the matter?     - Nothing.
怎么了 嘿
What is it? Hey?
- 真的没事 我…   - 瑞秋 别这样 什么
- Really, it's nothing. I'm...     - Rach, come on. What?
我一直在想 我跟宝宝要怎么独自活下去
I've just been thinking about how my baby and I are gonna be all alone.
你在说什么 罗斯呢
What are you talking about: "alone"? What about Ross?
拜托 他会有自己的家庭 双胞胎跟新波霸小姐
Oh, please. He'll be with his real family. The twins and little Miss New-Boobs.
好吧 我看那个女人多久了
Okay, how long was I watching that woman?
我那么说…
I'm just saying that, you know...
因为有一天 罗斯会认识别人…
...someday Ross is gonna meet somebody...
他会去过自己的生活
...and he's gonna have his own life.
对吧
Right?
我猜你说的对
Yeah, I guess so.
我没有想过 我要自己抚养这个宝宝
I just never thought I'd be raising this baby all by myself.
那真的很傻吧
Pretty dumb, huh?
你得听我说 听着
Hey, you listen to me. Listen to me.
你永远都不会是一个人
You are never, ever gonna be alone.
好吧 我发誓我不会让那种事发生
Okay? I promise I won't let that happen.
乔伊 喔 甜心 没有你我该怎么办
Oh, Joey. Oh, sweetie, what would I do without you?
你不必担心 好吗
You don't have to worry about that, okay?
你能再帮我 拿盒面纸来吗
Oh, honey, could you grab me my other box of tissues?
就在罗斯的外套下面
They're right on that chair under Ross' coat.
没问题
Sure.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
乔伊
Joey?
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
好吧
Okay.
（清洁间）
- 那真的是太神奇了   - 我知道
- That was amazing.     - I know.
你知道我们很可能已经永远地改变了我们的生活吗
Hey, do you realize that we may have just changed our lives forever?
我们可能已经开始组成了我们的家庭
We may have started our family.
九个月后我们可能会来这里…
Nine months from now, we could be here...
生下我们的孩子
...having our own baby.
要是没办法的话 我们得把宝宝生在桶子里
And if not, we got to do it on a bucket.